Yogesh Suresh Kapure

Flat no-13 Gangai Villa Society, Manaji Nagar

Nahre Pune-411041

Email ID: yogeshkapure5552@gmail.com

Mobile - 8928620966

OBJECTIVES

Cloud and Network Engineer with experience in successfully migrating networks to the AWS. Achieving a fully secure environment by creating various authentication processes and policies along the way to avoid space for human error. Focus on implementing new technologies while keeping company-wide data integral, available, and safe.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

- **4** Aws Solution Architect Global Certification Certified by Amazon 2024
- Crash Course on Python -Authorized by Google Offered Through Coursera- 2023
- **♣** SCNA Diploma By Silicon ValleyInstitute 2019
- **♣** Bachelor Of Commerce YCMU University- 2021-2024 (Expected)

EXPERIENCE

I have 4 Year plus years of hands-on experience in networking and cloud solutionarchitecture, I bring a wealth of expertise and proven skills to design and implement robust, scalable, and efficient solutions.

Sneha Synergy Solutions Pvt.Ltd | Executive IT

- > Duration :- December 2021 To Present
- > Designed and deployed wireless LAN solutions.
- Provided technical support to end-users, diagnosing and resolving hardware and network-related issues in a timely manner.
- > Resolved the DHCP and Access Point Related Issue.
- > Create a QR code software with help of google for Store the WIFI Users information and data uses.
- > Resolved the IT dose Software interfacing problem with SQL Server.
- > regular network performance monitoring, identifying and resolving issuespromptly to minimize downtime
- > Resolve the FortiNET FIREWALL issue in minimize downtime.
- > Resolve the 50 % Blue Screen Error in repetition.
- > Resolved the Network Printer and Networking Devices Issue.
- > plans to protect critical data and ensure business continuity Conducted regular network performance monitoring, identifying and resolving issues promptly to minimize downtime.
- Assisted in designing and implementing AWS cloud solutions under the guidance of senior architects, Gained hands-on experience with AWS services like EC2, S3, RDS, Lambda, VPC, and more
- > Optimized firewall performance through fine-tuning of rulebase, traffic inspection policies, and resource utilization parameters, resulting in improved throughput and reduced latency.
- Assisted in monitoring and optimizing AWS infrastructure for performance, cost efficiency, and resource utilization using AWS Cloud Watch.
- Actively contribute to team training sessions, sharing knowledge and best practices related to IT support and infrastructure management

Reliance jio infocomm limited| Jiofiber network hardware engineer

- > 2 Year experience
- > Duration :- May-2019 TO December-2021
- > Configuration of the LAN network and troubleshooting

- Printer management and installation
- Splicing of the fibre optic single mode maltimode
- Installation of O.S windows 10, window 8, windows 7 window XP
- Crimping and Testing of Cables
- Configuration of Router and Switches
- Solve the problem of router and network devices
- L2 network Mentainance.

Ovi Technoserve | desktop support and cctv engineer

- Duration: march 2018 to July 2019
 - Patching Crimping Cables make Straight and Cross cable
 - Various laptop and desktop installation, assemble and de-assemble
 - Troubleshooting of laptop and desktop
 - · Printer installation and printer sharing
 - Internet Connection Sharing
 - Installation of the o.s windows 7, windows 10, windows XP
 - Installation of IP camera, configuration of NVR
 - Installation of the analogue camera configuration of DVR
 - Software installation of IP and analogue camera
 - Solve the problem of NVR and DVR
 - Various laptop and desktop installation, assemble and de-assemble Troubleshooting of laptop and desktop when installing various hardware and software around the office Monitored the network

Technical Skills

- Hardware (A+): Computer Architecture, Types of Memory, Assembling, De- assembling, Troubleshooting, Formatting,
 Partitioning, details of various of component on the PCB, testing various part and component, common repair hardware
 related fault & software related fault.
- O.S. Installation: Installation of WindowsXP, Windows7, Windows8, Windows8.1, windows10
- <u>Networking (N+)</u>: Networking Concepts, Types of Networks, Network Topology, OSI models, Area Networks, TCP/IP protocol suite (IP, TCP, UDP, FTP),IP addressing and sub-netting, Routing concepts.
- Windows Server2008: Server Installation, Create ADDS, Installation of DHCP&DNS Server.
- Windows Server2012-2016: Server Installation, Create ADDS, Installation of DHCP&DNS Server. IP addressing and sub-netting, Routing concepts
 - DHCP, DNS, ADDS, Sharing, Domain, Child Domain
- <u>Routing and Switching</u>: knowledge of routing protocols such as OSPF, EIGRP, BGP, andswitching technologies like VLANs, STP.
- <u>Network Monitoring and Troubleshooting:</u> Ability to use network monitoring tools toanalyze network traffic, diagnose performance issues, and troubleshoot connectivity problems
- Wireless Networking: Experience with wireless LAN technologies, including configuring and securing wireless networks, understanding RF principles, and working with wireless controllers and Access Points.

CCTV Skills

- Installation of IP cameras.
- Installation of analog cameras.
- Solve the problem of IP and a analogue cameras.
- Solve the problem of DVR and NVR

I, Yogesh Kapure, declare that the above furnished information is true and correct to thebest of my knowledge.

Date:SignaturePlace:Yogesh Kapure